Sonsa kanashimi wo yatashisa ni
Jibunreshisa wo chikara ni Mayoi nagara
demo ii Arukidashite
Mou ii kai A little pause.
..
and we are back.
A little pause... and we are back.
So much for getting a good night's sleep,
stupid nerves.
And right off the bat, in the first match,
I have to go up against him.
But these chakra points, they're
undetectable even to my Sharingan eye.
I have on my team the man
who is probably the strongest
Genin ever to come out
of the Hidden Leaf Village.
That man, Neji Hyuga.
At last it begins.
Neji Hyuga's in the first match,
right?
Oh yeah, that guy's the number one rookie
from last year.
There's just no way we can miss that
match.
Neji Hyuga...
Yeah, but now I'm able to summon a Toad!
It'll be okay for sure!
But all of those guys look like nasty
competitors.
Huh?
Hinata?
Oh, Naruto!
So, why are you here?
The final competition...
Hmm... I just... it's nothing.
I came to check out this training field.
This is actually the place where I became
a Genin, so...
Oh, but... why are you here?
Uh, nothing!
No real reason, it doesn't matter anyway.
Oh, guess you're right.
Sorry.
Say, Hinata... Huh?
Neji, he's a cousin of yours, right?
Uh, yeah...
So is he... really strong?
Ugh... great.
But, I mean... you still might be able to
win, Naruto!
Yeah, I'm strong too, after all!
I know you can win, Naruto.
Huh?
Remember... that time...
when you cheered for me, I felt
like... like I was able to become
stronger than ever before.
Go, Hinata!
You can do it!
When the preliminaries ended, I was
finally able to like myself a little.
To anybody else, it might look like
absolutely nothing's changed about me...
But, I feel different.
Like I'm a better person now.
And I've been thinking... that... it was
all thanks to you, Naruto.
H-Hinata...
You really... do you really believe that's
true?
Huh?
I may look strong to you, but all I ever
do is mess things up.
I act tough because I'm so frustrated.
But underneath it all, I just feel like
I'm a huge failure.
No, that's not true!
Hm?
Even when you messed up, you were
always a... um... how can I say this...
a proud failure from
my point of view.
Huh?
When I look at you, you just fill me with
such... such admiration.
I'm not saying that you're perfect.
I mean, no one is.
But when you do make
a mistake, you have the
guts to pick yourself
up and keep trying.
I think that courage... to keep going no
matter what... is what real strength is.
I just think... you're an incredibly
strong person, Naruto.
Huh?
Thanks, Hinata.
I needed that.
Even though I'm completely
used to being the underdog,
I guess this time I was
just really feeling the strain.
I was really down, which isn't like me at
all.
But I feel 100% better now!
I'm glad you do.
Alright, I'm off to the match.
Thanks again!
Hinata... Huh?
I kinda... thought you were... um...
What?
Gloomy, timid, always terrified,
and basically completely weird.
Oh... But you know what?
I actually like...
...people like you!
Oh yeah!
Don't forget to come watch me wipe up the
floor with Neji in the final competition!
Huh?
Oh no!
I gotta get going!
And fast!
Oh man!
I'm gonna be late!
See you later, Hinata!
Hey, Hinata!
Sorry I'm so late.
Oh well, she knows matches until later
anyway.
Huh?
Hey!
What's with you?
Hmm?
Hey, wait!
Where's Sasuke?
I'm fighting Dosu, but he's missing too.
Hey, knock it off.
Quit your fidgeting, you two.
Stand up straight and present yourself
proudly to the spectators.
Huh?
You
guys are the heroes of this final
competition.
No sign of Sasuke yet?
No.
A team of Anbu black ops are searching for
him.
But so far, they've found nothing.
He may already be in Orochimaru's hands.
In which case, of course, we may never
find him.
I understand.
Aha!
You made it!
Welcome, Lord Kazekage!
You must be weary having come all this
way.
Not at all.
I'm only glad that for your sake,
the arena is here in the Leaf Forest.
A village.
As strong as you are, I'm sure a long
journey would have proven difficult for you.
At your age.
Isn't it about time you decided who will
succeed you as Hokage?
Hmm?
You act as if I were an old man.
There's plenty of life left in me.
No, I plan on staying here for some time
to come.
Welcome.
Now then, it's time for the final rounds
to begin.
Welcome all, and our deepest
thanks for coming here to the
village hidden in the leaves
for this year's Chunin selection.
We have come to the final
competition between the
eight candidates who made
it through the preliminaries.
We ask that no one leaves until all the
matches have been completed.
Now, everyone enjoy!
You said eight candidates.
Aren't you missing one?
Hmm... Oh, there's one more
thing before we get started.
Look it over.
Huh?
There's been a slight change in the
matchups.
But now it's set, so everyone take one
last look at who you'll be facing.
I thought I was supposed to fight an extra
match.
Hey...
So that Dosu guy dropped out.
Uh, question?
Question!
What is it?
I was, uh, just wondering what'll happen
to Sasuke.
I mean, if he doesn't show up.
If a candidate is not here in the arena at
the time his name is called...
He forfeits the match.
It doesn't make sense!
Sasuke's not the type to miss this,
even if he had to drag himself here!
What is it, Gaara?
Where are you going?
To remind myself I'm alive.
Sasuke, one more time.
Hmm...
What's wrong?
It's obvious you're hiding there,
thirsting for blood.
Save me the trouble and come out.
So you're the one called Gaara.
If there's something
you wanted to say before
the final rounds, go
ahead and spit it out.
When we finally fight...
It won't be to advance to the next stage,
but solely for survival.
One seeking to destroy the other.
Only the last one standing will feel the
full value of his existence.
You're not talking about
a match, you're talking
about some kind of
grudge bout to the death.
It's crazy.
Uchiha...
In the depths of your soul...
It's what you want too, isn't it?
You want to confirm the value of your
existence, don't you?
To know if you're truly as powerful as you
think you are.
Whose existence is stronger?
Yours?
Or the one facing you with murder in his
eyes?
No... After all my warnings not
to draw attention to himself...
He wouldn't have killed
Sasuke Uchiha too... Would he?
All right, listen up.
The terrain's different, but the rules are
the same as before.
That is, that there are no rules.
The match continues till one
candidate acknowledges defeat... Or dies.
That being said, if I
determine that a match
is over, I can step in
and stop it at any time.
And no arguments permitted.
Understood?
These are the opponents for the first
match.
Naruto Uzumaki and Neji Hyuga.
Those two stay.
The rest of you can go to the waiting
area.
Hey Hinata, look.
These seats are free.
Oh, thanks.
I think this is gonna be an interesting
match.
Who would have believed that little squirt
would survive this long?
Yeah.
He's been one lucky kid so far.
But his luck's about to run out.
He'll never survive this one.
Yeah, it's gonna be painful.
Going up against one of the easiest.
The Hyuga clan?
He doesn't have a chance.
Yeah, I thought that too.
At first.
And look what happened.
He's out there.
And I'm sitting up here on my butt.
Huh?
Yeah, Hakamaru, what is it?
What the?
Are you sure?
Where?
Hmm?
Huh?
Up there!
What the hell are the Anbu Black Ops doing
here?
Something's going on.
You got anything to say to me?
Only what I told you the last time.
I vow to win!
He has the look.
He's calmer now, more sure of himself.
So much the better for me.
I can't wait to see the look of despair on
your face.
When you learn that your foolish vow is
impossible to keep.
Are we gonna stand here talking all day?
Let's get going!
Show me what you got!
Alright, now let the first match...
Begin!
Watch closely, Hanabi.
There's no one in the Hyuga clan who has
inherited such a strong Kekkei Genkai.
His is stronger than your older sister's.
Stronger than hers?
Perhaps even stronger than yours.
Huh?
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
That's using your head, Naruto.
That oughta confuse him.
Well, isn't he something?
That Shadow Clone Jutsu is a Joanie-level
technique.
Where'd that kid ever pick up a technique
like that?
This match could be more interesting than
we thought.
Shadow Clones... I see.
Quite clever.
He's distributed his chakra
evenly among them so
that even my Byakugan
can't pick out the real one.
No matter.
You can't hide for long.
Ha!
Well, we'll just see about that!
If you're coming, then come on!
Hmph!
It's no use.
No matter how many times Naruto attacks
him, Neji can win on his defense alone.
Not bad, but let's see you do that again!
Well, you have my thanks!
Here's the clue.
A severed part of me?
That's enough of it now!
This man... He must have
eyes in the back of his head!
Sakuya!
You thought you could be Hokage?
It's absurd.
Never.
These eyes of mine show me many things.
One thing they've shown me.
People's limitations are set, fixed,
and unchangeable.
Only a fool wastes his time trying to
become something he can never be.
A fool, huh?
Not this crap again!
Who are you to judge what a person can or
can't be?
Do you think anyone can be Hokage?
That all it takes is a little hard work?
Open your eyes.
Of all the shinobi in all the world,
think how few ever become Hokage.
They were born destined to be Hokage.
It's not something you become merely by
trying to become it.
They were chosen by destiny.
Each person is given his own path to
follow.
And he must follow it.
Obediently.
To the end.
There is only one destiny we all share
equally.
Death.
There's hatred in his eyes.
Hatred for the main branch of the family.
Yeah?
So what?
You can think that way if you want!
People always tell me I just don't know
when to give up!
Shadowkid, Clown Jutsu!
Put on a good show, will you, Naruto?
You know.
I've got a tough job to do.
And I'd like to be entertained while I'm
doing it.
This is ridiculous!
We're not even getting close to this guy!
You think I can be fooled with a trick
like that?
Conjure all the clones you want!
You can't hide from me!
You're the one keeping out of range for
fear of my striking your chakra points.
Like this.
The more the others attack, the more you
stand out for holding back.
The match is over.
I told you it was pointless.
Oh, yeah?
And I told you it was a mistake to count
me out!
But how?
Let's see if this sucks.
Wait and go, Naruto!
Naruto...
He held one of these clones back to
deceive me!
To lure me into a trap!
You thought I'd be too much of a chicken
to attack you myself?
Well, think again!
Help!
Go!
Huh?
What the heck was that?
Did you really think you'd won?
But that was...
Rotation.
We'll see about that!
Neji can see almost 360 degrees with his
Byakugan.
It's pointless.
He can detect any attack as soon as it's
launched.
That's when his real defense comes into
play.
The 8 Trigrams Palm Rotation.
The moment he senses an attack,
Neji discharges an intense, focused burst
of chakra from the chakra points in his
body.
Then, by rotating his body
quickly, he builds up enough
energy to not only block,
but repel his attacker.
Normally, chakra emitted from chakra
points is difficult to control.
Even Jonin can usually
only utilize chakra from a
single body part at a
time, like the hands or feet.
But Neji's mastery of the Gentle Fist
Taijutsu is so great that he can emit
chakra from several
places, warding off
simultaneous attacks
from multiple directions.
It's an ultimate defense, even more
impenetrable than Gaara's Shell of Sand.
Nothing can get through it.
But... I thought... only father could...
It's a secret ninja art,
for generations reserved
only for the main
household of the Hyuga clan.
But Neji has somehow discovered it on his
own.
Incredible as it may seem, he's come far.
No one should be surprised.
You haven't even begun to see his full
powers.
This is the end for you.
You're in range, and you can't escape my
eight trigrams.
Gentle Fist art.
Eight trigrams, sixty-four palms.
That stance... it can't be...
Samurai Invisibility.
Eight trigrams.
Two palms.
Four palms.
Eight palms.
Sixty palms.
Thirty-two palms.
Have we been surpassed by this branch
family?
Truly, my brother, you've been denied what
is rightfully yours.
I have now struck all 64 of your chakra
points.
You're lucky to still be breathing.
Come on!
Well, must be frustrating
to realize how utterly
hopeless it all was, this
little dream of yours.
Bushy brow...
Hinata...
No way...
Come on...
Impossible...
How could he...
I told you... I just don't know when to
give up.
Hey!
You're coughing up blood!
What is it?
Oh, wow.
You must still be injured from your match.
Let me have a look at her.
Who are you?
It's all right.
You can trust me.
Stop this madness.
You'll only get more of the same.
I have nothing against you, personally.
I've got plenty against you.
I don't know what you mean.
You mocked Hinata, calling her a failure.
All that stuff about the great Hyuga
clan, main household, branch families...
What a bunch of crap!
It doesn't give you the right to decide
who's a failure.
That's what I've got against you!
Hey, what are you.
..
Don't worry.
I'm a doctor.
Very well.
As you're so interested, I'll tell you
about it.
The Hyuga clan's heritage of hatred!
For generations, the main
household of our clan has
practiced a secret ninjutsu,
known as the Curse Mark Jutsu.
Curse Mark Jutsu?
Can you actually see it?
The Curse Mark is the symbol of a bird
locked in its cage.
It's the mark of those who are bound to a
destiny they cannot escape.
... ... ...
Is... is that...
That's... the curse mark?
I was four years old when
the leaders of my clan branded
this symbol on my forehead
with their curse mark jutsu.
On that same day, a great celebration took
place in the Hidden Leaf Village.
After many years of war, a peace agreement
had at last been reached with the Land of
Lightning, and they had
sent the Head Cloud Ninja
to sign the treaty and
join in the celebration.
Everyone was there to welcome our old
enemies.
Every genin and jonin in the Leaf Village.
Only one clan was absent.
The Hyuga clan.
Because this was the day on which the heir
to the main household was to turn three.
It was Lady Hinata.
Lady Hinata's third birthday.
Her father, Lord Hiyashi Hyuga,
is sitting up there.
He and my father, Hisashi, are twin
brothers.
And yet, he entered into the world first.
So he is head of the family.
The firstborn.
While my father, his twin brother, is
banished to a lesser branch of the family.
So Lady Hinata is three years old.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Lady Hinata.
She is a really cute kid.
Neji.
There is something that you must know.
It's your destiny to protect her.
And the Hyuga bloodline.
The Hyuga... bloodline?
My Father!
Hisashi, it is time I took Neji under my
wing.
... Yes.
It was then, on the day the heir to the
main household turned three, that the
curse mark was put on me and I was made a
bird in a cage.
This is more than a mark.
It is also the instrument by which they
keep us in our place.
And we live with it every day.
Only in death are we free of it.
This is how the power of the Byakugan is
kept sealed away.
Only the Hyuga possess the secret of this
unique form of Kekkei Genkai.
And of course, there are many who would
steal it from us.
That is why we exist.
It is the purpose of the Branch family to
defend that secret.
And to serve the keepers
of the secret, the main
household, obediently and
without question, for eternity.
That is our destiny.
Or was.
Until that dreadful night.
They went too far.
When they murdered my father.
One night, someone entered the main
household and abducted Lady Hinata.
Lord Hiyashi quickly caught and killed the
man.
And who was this intruder?
Stealing through the shadows in the dead
of night?
Wearing a mask over his face?
It was none other than the head-cloud
ninja of the Land of Lightning.
The man who had just signed an alliance
with us.
It was obvious to everyone that he was
after the secret of the Byakugan.
But the Land of Lightning professed shock
at this willful murder of their ninja.
They claimed that the Hidden Leaf Village
was in violation of the treaty,
and they demanded recompense.
A life for a life.
The Land of Lightning demanded the death
of the person who had slain their ninja.
If there was to be peace, Lord Hiyashi
must die.
The Leaf Village accepted their terms.
But father, then how?
And so to avert a war, a man was killed.
But not Hiyashi.
My father, his twin brother, was killed in
his place.
In order to protect the main household.
Only in death was my father finally free
of this evil curse mark.
They were so much alike.
Twin brothers.
But their destinies had been determined.
Long ago.
When one was born a few seconds after the
other.
And this match is the same.
Your destiny was decided the moment I was
chosen as your opponent.
Oh, yeah?
Well, we won't know that until you beat
me, will we?
Okay.
So your father was killed a long time ago.
And I know it wasn't fair.
And maybe you're upset about that.
I understand.
But that's got nothing to do with destiny.
If you think I'm buying that, you're
wrong.
You will never understand.
Proctor.
It's over.
You're a failure.
Wait.
Don't walk away from me.
I'm not done yet.
I don't quit.
And I don't go back on my word.
That's my nindo, my ninja way.
I've heard those words before.
All this destiny crap.
Well, if you really believe it,
why are you the one walking away?
You impudent little brat.
Why waste my breath explaining it to you?
You don't know what it's like to be
branded with a mark that sets you apart.
A mark that can never be wiped away.
Oh, yeah.
I know what that's like.
Well... Big deal.
Who cares?
You... worthless little... Man.
You think you've got troubles?
I've got news for you, Neji.
You're not the only special one around
here.
Did you ever think that Hinata might be
suffering as much as you are?
It's not her fault that her father was
born ahead of yours.
But you resent her for it.
You disrespect her, even when she's trying
so hard to improve herself.
All she wanted was your respect.
That's what she was fighting for,
even though it almost killed her.
And what was that all about, anyway?
I thought it was your
destiny to serve the main
household, not to
beat it to a bloody pulp.
After all you've said about
how you can't fight your
destiny, you don't really
believe in it either, do you?
The color's coming back to her face!
He did it!
Whoa, these Anbu Black Ops... They're
really good.
She'll be alright now.
She just needs rest.
I have blocked all 64 of your chakra
points.
How are you planning to keep fighting when
you can't use your chakra against me?
...
Have you ever felt the presence of a
different chakra?
You have two types of chakra, but you must
use up all of one before you can assess
the other, and thus increase the total
amount of chakra you can use.
That's it!
I can use the Nine-Tailed Fox's chakra!
Okay, you stinkin' fox!
If you're there, give me your strength!
Proctor, this has gone on long enough.
I suggest you stop the match.
If he's foolish enough
to continue to fight, I
will not be responsible
for what happens to him.
Hmph.
Fine.
Why bother?
You have no chakra to use!
Oh yeah!
Don't forget to come watch me wipe off the
floor with Neji in the final competition!
The loser beating the gifted genius
through sheer willpower!
Hmph.
Why fight a hopeless battle trying to defy
your destiny?
Because people called me a failure!
I'll prove them wrong!
CHAAAAAAAAACK!
Chakra is that!
Or is it even chakra at all?
So sweet!
Here goes!
Rotation!uen!
Take this!
Okay, you!
So I hear you like close combat,
huh?
It may be the Hyuga way to cave into
destiny, it's not mine!
If you think it's futile to fight,
then don't!
Just stand there and take it!
Quickly!
Must use my rotation!
I'll change the way of the Hyuga plan!
It is!
After I become Hokage!
Man, that's some chakra that kid's got.
Never seen anything like it.
No way that Hyuga kid could have...
Sorry, but this is reality.
You're a failure.
This match is over.
It's over.
Can't move!
I
should have guessed you'd use that shadow
clone jutsu.
It's your specialty after all.
I was careless.
For the record, I failed the graduation
exam three times.
Because there was this one jutsu that was
always on the exam.
And it tripped me up every time.
It was the one jutsu that I just couldn't
master.
My clones were pathetic.
That's right, I flunked the clone jutsu
every time.
Okay.
So don't come whining to me with this
destiny stuff.
And stop trying to tell me you can't
change what you are.
You can do it too.
Because after all, unlike me, you're not a
failure.
The winner is... Naruto Uzumaki.
Huh?
Amazing!
That's a cutie!
Yeah!
Even after that fight, he has the energy
to run around.
That kid has amazing stamina.
Yeah!
Naruto just keeps getting stronger.
Wow!
He did it!
He won the fight!
Mhm.
He's on the track to success.
And he's kinda cute too.
I hate to admit it, Naruto.
Naruto, but I envy you.
Watching your battle has made me realize
that I have to work really hard too,
or I'll never get anywhere.
Naruto defeated Neji?
Oh man, I can't believe it.
And I thought Naruto was the same as me,
one of the Dorky Uncool guys.
Dorky Uncool?
Now everyone's saying that he's gonna make
something big of himself.
Just great.
I doubt I can beat him now.
This is really bad.
I've never felt so depressed.
What a drag.
He was able to draw upon the fox's chakra
all by himself.
Yeah.
Even the people from the Hidden Leaf
Village seemed totally surprised.
Remarkable.
When did he learn to control the chakra of
a nine-tailed fox to such a degree?
Even a caged bird was surprised.
He's smart enough, and
will be able to figure out
how to open the door
to its cage with its beak.
The dream of flying and breaking free is
too great to resist.
But this time you lost.
This crowd is certainly energized.
That's because it was a terrific fight.
Of course, it's that too.
But...
Hmm?
It's also anticipation.
It's likely that the shinobi leaders,
feudal lords, and other spectators are
looking forward to this next match more
than anything.
There's been no news of Sasuke yet.
And there's the issue of Orochimaru.
Please, before everyone starts to make
trouble, disqualify Sasuke.
Hey, what's going on here?
Hurry up and start the next match!
Come on, let's go!
Sometime before night falls!
I wonder what's going on.
The next match.
Sasuke should be here by now.
Sasuke...
That Sasuke... What in the world does he
think he's doing?
Forfeiting?
A wise man never courts danger,
leading to a wise decision.
Huh?
What are you talking about?
He's definitely going to be here,
believe it!
Hm?
But seriously, what is he doing?
If he doesn't get here soon, he's going to
be disqualified.
I have no choice.
Sasuke is disqualified.
Right.
Lord Hokage, I ask you
to consider waiting a
little longer before
disqualifying Sasuke Uchiha.
I understand your point.
But no matter how
excellent a shinobi he may be,
he's late and we can't
make special allowances.
If there's no clear reason to make all the
shinobi leaders and feudal lords wait,
then there's no reason not to disqualify
him immediately.
I see.
Then it's good I do have a clear reason.
Huh?
Including myself, most of the
shinobi leaders and feudal lords
here came simply because
they want to see the next match.
Yes, but still... He's the only
remaining member of the Uchiha clan.
And I know that the
Land of Wind especially is
hoping for a bout between
Sasuke and our Gaara.
Lord Hokage...
There's no guarantee there is.
That Sasuke will come, but...
Very well, then.
We will make an exception.
We shall postpone this match and wait.
But Lord Hokage, I must protest.
Inform the proctor right away.
Yes, sir.
However, it's most unusual for you to
insist so strongly, Lord Kazekage.
To display the full
strength of our village's
ninja, no opponent
but an Uchiha will do.
This is a big chance for Sasuke,
yes, but a big opportunity for us as well.
You've got to be kidding me!
Come on, get in the S8!
Boo!
I understand.
This is ridiculous!
Listen, everyone.
One of the competitors from the next
battle has not arrived yet.
So, we're going to postpone
this match briefly and simply
jump ahead to the battle that
would have followed this one.
Just what in the world could Sasuke be
doing anyway?
So cool!
That means Sasuke is still in this!
That's good!
Hey!
That means my battle's one match closer
now!
What a drag!
Then on to the next battle!
So, Shino and Kankuro, come down.
My match doesn't matter at all now.
Besides, I don't want to reveal
the mechanism of my trained
crow puppet to the enemy
before our plan comes to fruition.
Proctor!
I withdraw!
Huh?
What?
I withdraw, so please, advance to the next
match!
Whoa!
What is this?
Sigh...
Due to Kankuro's withdrawal, Shino Aburame
wins by default.
What?
We came here for a real match!
Come on!
I don't want to see this!
Ah!
No,
I'd like a real match!
Wanna go with me?
Let's go!
Shino!
Oh, please, help me!
What was that?
After all you've done for me, you're going
to fight him?
Yeah, I won't do that!
You might be the one who won't fight me.
Huh?
I know it's hard to make a living if
you leave... Shikamaru Nara, come on!
Great.
If it's gonna be like this, maybe I'll
withdraw too.
Alright!
Go on, Shikamaru, you can do it!
Damn that Naruto.
They
don't care about this match.
Just the warm-up for the main event.
All they care about is watching Sasuke.
Listen to me, the jerks.
What is it?
You planning on giving up too?
And to top it off, my opponent's a girl.
Again.
Well, he never was very driven.
But this?
Come on, come on!
Get up and fight!
Get it together, Shikamaru!
You gonna get going sometime this year?
Well, if you won't fight, I'll move,
I will!
Hey, I didn't start the match yet.
I forgot.
This girl's a Spunky one.
I hate Spunky.
It really doesn't make
a whole lot of difference
to me whether I ever
become a Chunin or not.
But I guess maybe I shouldn't let myself
get beaten by a female.
So, let's do it!
He's quick enough when it comes to running
away.
I know it's not very classy for a guy to
clobber a girl.
But whoever said I was classy?
He's trying to lure me into the shadow of
that tree.
I'm not falling for that.
So why do I always have to fight girls?
It sucks, man.
Go for it, Shikamaru!
Use the super ultimate technique on her
and take that bitch down!
Yo, is this seat taken?
I thought you were in the hospital.
Your stomach's okay now?
What's up?
I thought Sasuke's match was supposed to
be next.
I'm sure Sasuke's fine.
He'll be here any minute now.
Man, you'd think her puppy died or
something.
Never expected to see Shikamaru in the
final.
Weird.
What do you mean?
Come on.
Shikamaru may not have as much fighting
spirit as some other people.
And okay, his technique is pretty lousy,
but he's strong at strategy.
So strong, in fact, that
without him we might
not have gotten through
the preliminary round.
Huh?
Maybe.
What's more, you should have seen how he
threw himself into the arena.
I'm telling you, Choji, he seems unusually
aggressive.
I think he's gonna show us his passionate
side today!
Yeah!
Go, Shikamaru!
Sometimes I wish I was a cloud.
Just floating along...
Going wherever the breeze takes me.
That's my style.
I'm just not into putting effort into
stuff.
The only reason I became a ninja was so I
could do whatever I wanted.
Jeez, who knew it'd be so much work?
Hmm...
Hmm... Hmm...
Hmm... Oh, well... Heh.
A guy's gotta do what a guy's gotta do.
What's he thinking behind that stupid
grin?
Is he mocking me?
Ninja Art!
Wind-Side Choo-Choo!
Yeah!
Ha-ha-ha!
I remember.
This is how she beat me in our fight.
Ruin her can get past it!
Now I get it.
Almost got me.
Aren't you clever?
With that shadow possession jutsu of yours,
you can manipulate any shadow you're in.
The wall's shadow, for instance.
But there's a limit, isn't there?
No matter how thin you stretch it,
it'll only reach so far.
Isn't that right?
You got me.
And now I know just where that limit is.
Even using the wall's shadow, his jutsu
can only reach to here.
15 meters, 32 centimeters.
That's the range of his attack.
If I can just stay outside this line,
he can't touch me.
She's measured his range.
This plays right to his strength.
She's better at long range attacks anyway.
This match is as good as over.
What's that?
A hand sign?
No, he's not making a hand sign.
It's something more like a habit.
A habit?
That kid.
He's like an old man.
He likes to take things slowly.
Heh.
I mean really slowly.
That's why he's so good at games like Go
and Shogi.
He's always challenging me to a match.
Whenever he gets stuck in a move,
he does that thing with his hands.
What does it mean?
He's working on a strategy.
Huh?
All the times we've played, I've never
beaten him.
Well that's fine but... this is a
real fight, not some game of Shogi.
Strategy on a gameboard
is no different from strategy
on the field of battle and
all great generals know that.
Shikamaru's got the mind of a great
general.
Just you watch.
You could've fooled me.
Don't forget I saw the test scores when we
grouped the Genin.
His were no better than Naruto's,
maybe worse.
He's a little too strong.
I'd say he's a bit more powerful.
He says the act of putting pencil to paper
is a drag.
It's too much work for him.
He'd rather take a nap than a written
exam.
He would, huh?
I didn't say he wasn't lazy.
But he was so good at strategy games I had
him take an IQ test.
Of course I had to deceive him into
thinking it was just another game.
As I suspected, his score was almost off
the charts.
Beyond genius.
The kid has an IQ of over 200.
200?
So you have some fighting spirit after
all.
No use in hiding!
Are you sure he's even got a strategy?
Look at that.
He can't get anywhere near her.
Go, Shikamaru!
Do something!
Don't waste your breath.
He'll give up soon.
This is way too much work for him.
You can't hide forever.
Come out, coward!
Forget
it.
As long as I stay on this side of the
line, he can't touch me.
What the?
It's still coming!
You're pretty quick on your toes.
Now I see what you've been up to.
You weren't just hiding.
You were killing time.
Waiting for the sun to get lower.
And the shadow of that wall to get longer.
The longer the shadows, the farther your
range is, right?
Alright.
If I just calculate the height of the sun
and measuring the distance he's gained
from his previous attack, I can still keep
out of range.
No problem.
Tamari!
Over your head!
Oh no!
I've got you now!
He made a parachute out of his jacket to
create an extra shadow.
Oof!
She learns fast, I'll give her that.
The longer this match takes, the lower the
sun gets.
The longer the shadows, the farther his
range.
Eek.
Time to finish this.
Now!
Clone jutsu!
What?
My... my body!
It's frozen!
It took a while, but my shadow possession
finally worked.
No!
How the hell did he do that?
Amazing.
He was thinking three moves ahead all
along.
As I said, that's Shikamaru's strength.
Impossible.
How could he have caught me with his
shadow?
It couldn't reach this far.
Hmph.
Look behind you.
I'll let you.
Out of the hole?
How?
Don't you recognize that hole?
It's where Naruto popped out of the ground
and knocked Neji for a loop.
The hole in front of you is where he went
into the ground.
The two are connected.
Now I see.
I never thought of the shadows
underground.
That was your mistake.
The whole time I thought I
was keeping out of range of
his shadow jutsu, when I
was really walking right into it.
Amazing.
This slacker clown outsmarted me.
The next move is checkmate.
He's got control of my body.
I'm helpless.
Look at everybody.
A minute ago they were throwing things at
him.
Well, who would have ever thought the
guy'd turn out to be a ringer?
Yeah!
He did it!
He pulled off an upset!
You got her!
Way to go!
The hell with it.
I give up.
Huh?
He what?
You gotta be kidding me!
Loser!
See?
I told you he'd give up.
Looks like I know Shikumaru a little bit
better than you do, huh?
What?
What did you say?
I used up all my chakra on that shadow
possession jutsu.
I'm good for about another ten seconds.
That's it.
Bummer.
And here I'd already planned out the next
two hundred moves in my head.
But my chakra's running low.
Anyway, if I was to win this thing,
it would just mean more work.
This guy is something else.
The winner is... Tamari!
Tamari!
Damn it!
Ahhhh!
What a waste!
Why!?
What is he thinking!?
Doesn't he wanna be a Cd?
What can you say?
It's Shikumaru.
I wonder...you think he has the motivation
for this?
I've wondered that same thing myself,
so many times.
You on.
Even so, his tactics and ingenuity are far
beyond those of your typical genin.
If that had been a real
mission and he'd been
leading a squad, they
would have succeeded.
The battle was won the moment he caught
Tamari in that shadow possession.
I guess you could say he won the battle
but lost the match.
He may not be as motivated as some of the
others, but you know it's not such a bad
thing for a squad leader to trust his head
more than his gut.
He'll get in a lot less trouble that way.
You said it.
A squad with a hotshot for a leader is a
squad that's not going to survive very long.
Some of these kids don't
understand there's not much point
in completing a mission if
your whole team gets wiped out.
That's not what being a Chunin is about.
If you're scoring them on that,
Naruto and Neji failed the test.
Still, I can't help feeling Shikamaru gave
up too soon.
What do you think?
Well, one thing I'm sure of.
He's got a lot better chance than that
Naruto kid.
That lazy son of a...
I'm gonna give him a piece of my mind!
And to think that lazy kid's gonna be a
Chunin.
Hey, I wanna talk to you, you idiot!
Who you calling an idiot, idiot?
Why'd you give up?
You really that lazy or you just a big
chicken?
Hey, it's over.
Let's just forget it, okay?
Are you kidding?
No, it's not okay!
You had that match won and you just gave
up!
Would you skip it?
Are you forgetting?
There's another match.
What kind of guy does that?
I mean to quit right when...
Huh?
Another match?
Yeah, that's right!
I heard that Sasuke Uchiha had to pull out
of the match.
What?
No way!
Come on, Uchiha!
Let's go!
Well, it seems fairly clear this Uchiha is
bound to win.
I wouldn't be so sure.
I like the look of this stranger from the
Sand Village.
I'm putting my money on the mystery man.
Lord Hokage, I'm afraid there's still no
sign of Sasuke Uchiha.
He hasn't arrived at the arena.
Right.
Then we have no choice.
Surely we can give him another ten
minutes.
My lord?
This is what the crowd's been waiting for.
It would be a cruel blow to cancel.
They might even turn ugly.
After waiting this long, surely another
ten minutes won't hurt.
There's something in what Lord Kazekage
says, I must admit.
Go.
Tell Genma my decision.
Right.
I see.
A ten minute reprieve, huh?
Sasuke!
Huh?
Hey, is that who I think it is?
Man, I swear if he doesn't show,
I'll kill him!
I swear I'll kill him!
Welcome.
Glad you both could make it.
Yeah, what a surprise.
Go right on in.
Roger!
Hmm.
Well, Lee, ready to go?
Yes, sir!
You've missed most of the first round.
The only match left is between Sasuke
Uchiha and that Gaara kid.
But what happened with Naruto and Neji?
Well, that was the most amazing thing.
The Hyuga kid actually got beat.
Naruto beat Neji?
That is something.
Well done, Naruto.
Congratulations.
Lee will always be a winner where it
counts.
In his heart.
Tamari, what's going on?
What's up?
Is he really not going to show?
He'll be here.
Huh?
He'll definitely be here.
We're a little late.
Hope we didn't miss the party.
And you are?
I'm Sasuke Uchiha.
Sasuke!
Huh.
So you decided to show up after all.
I was betting you wouldn't come to see me.
Sooner or later, you'd have to face me!
Well, don't get too full of yourself.
You're still a loser.
Anyway, what about you, Naruto?
Tell me, did you win?
You know it!
Sorry if we kept you waiting.
But, um... how late are we?
I mean, it's not like Sasuke's...
well, disqualified or anything, right?
You know you were so late that we extended
the deadline for you.
No is not disqualified.
Oh, that's a relief.
Listen, Sasuke.
Don't lose to him.
Got it.
You are one of the ones I want to fight
the most.
Don't lose!
Because I want to fight you myself!
Got it.
You are one of the ones I want to fight
the most.
Is that really him?
A minute ago she was cheering just as loud
for Shikamaru.
Jeez, women are fickle.
So, I'm yesterday's news already.
Well, I can't say I blame him.
I'm looking forward to this one myself.
Sakura, what's it like to be on such an
amazing team?
What do you mean?
You know.
First, Naruto surprises everyone by
beating Neji Hyuga.
Oh, and then you've got Sasuke who's like
the superstar.
Everyone wants to see his match.
You're like the all-star team!
Sasuke is fighting that sand ninja,
Gaara, whom I was powerless against.
And Naruto won against Neji, whom I'd
always wanted to defeat.
And all I get to do is stand here and
watch.
It's so frustrating.
Oh, Lee.
At last.
All right, Gaara.
Come down here.
Come on, Naruto.
They don't need us here.
Oh, uh...
Let's go.
And I'm gonna take the stairs this time,
if you don't mind.
Come on.
Are you still upset that I gave you a
little push?
You ought to be grateful.
This isn't good.
He's got that look again.
Okay.
Listen, Gaara.
Don't let him throw off the plan.
Now's not the time to talk to him.
Not unless you want to get yourself
killed.
Hey, let's go.
Will you hurry up?
Come on!
Relax, Naruto.
You're gonna give yourself an ulcer.
Huh?
What is it?
You puny kids think this tournament is
about you.
But it's really about the people who bet
on you.
Or against you, in your case.
You see, our master's got a lot of money
on the other guy to win.
Got it.
That means... you gotta lose.
No!
I'm
sorry, but we do have to finish this!
What a shame.
Now we'll have to choose our fate.
But not at all.
We can't let this go.
We can't let them get away with it.
They're no match for us.
I'm totally sorry.
Hopefully we'll have a chance to get our
revenge.
But I think you're in your best place
right now.
Even so, don't let them get away with
this.
I'm sure you're going to get a little more
help from your team.
I've realized your purpose in time,
and it's true.
That could have been us just now.
I've never in my life seen anyone kill
like that without even batting an eye.
Things don't look so good for your friend
at all.
Sasuke!
Alright.
The rules for this match are the same as
in the preliminaries.
The match continues until one of you dies
or admits defeat.
However, I can stop the match.
But that's solely my decision.
Hello, guy.
How are you feeling, Lee?
Are you alright?
Kakashi.
Kakashi-sensei!
Oh, right.
Sorry about that.
You must have been worried.
Sorry for not keeping in touch.
Uh-oh.
Sakura's gonna get really mad!
I don't mind.
That's okay.
Listen, sensei.
Hmm?
You know that there was a mark on Sasuke's
neck, right?
It's nothing to worry about.
So, that's that.
Eight of them.
Eight members of the Anbu Black Ops in an
arena this size?
That's nowhere near enough.
What could Lord Hokage be thinking?
Well, not knowing how the enemy is going
to act, the Anbu Black Ops have probably
been dispersed and stationed around the
key parts of the village.
Huh?
It's starting.
We can't afford to let our guard down.
But for now, at least, we need to watch
this match.
Haha!
This is gonna be awesome!
Kakashi, I'm gonna be
carefully watching your
pupil to see if your
training was any good.
After all, I'm still your rival.
Hm?
Sorry, did you say something?
Begin!
So this is the sand Kakashi talked about.
Please!
I beg you!
Don't get so mad at me!
Mother...
What in the world is he talking about?
Early, Arai.
I know I made you taste such awful blood.
I'm so sorry.
But this time, I'm sure that it'll taste
so very good.
He's gone.
Thank goodness, he's finally calmed down.
...
Then, if it's supposed to be, then I
should be the doctor.
Come on... ... ...
... ...
...
A little pause.
..
and we are back.
Oh, he's almost as fast as Lee's normal
speed.
It is almost like a mirror image of my own
taijutsu.
So that's your sand armor, huh?
Come on.
If you won't do it, then I will!
What's the matter, Gaara?
Is that all you've got?
Amazing!
I'm going to tear off all your armor!
His speed's basically the same as Lee's
with his wigs removed.
His training... What did you two do?
Huh?
To get to such a level... in a mere month!
Sasuke has copied Lee's taijutsu with his
Sharingan.
So during this time...
In the Taijutsu training I did with Sasuke,
I simply had him imagine Lee's movement.
..
and copy it.
Sasuke mastered that Taijutsu only because
he knew Lee.
Of course, Sasuke had to work very hard to
master it, even with his Sharingan.
If Kakashi saw the battle
between Gaara and Lee,
why did he have Sasuke
master only Taijutsu?
What then was left for me in this
existence?
Why go on living?
But in order to live you need a purpose.
To exist for no reason is the same as
being dead.
What is this guy talking about?
Then in time the answer came to me.
To put it simply, my reason for living is
in the killing of others.
For years I lived in fear of those who
were sent to murder me.
But now I am at peace.
Shigemaru, we have to go talk to
Kakashi-sensei right now!
What are you planning to do?
Hey, wait!
I've gotta stop him!
I've gotta stop the match!
You just lost him for in vain.
So he's used all the sand as a shield.
Because of the sand's density, I didn't
think he could create something this hard.
So he's absolutely protected.
Kakashi-sensei!
Hey!
Naruto!
What is it, Naruto?
Sensei, please!
You just have to stop this match right
away!
What?
The guy Sasuke is fighting is completely
different than the rest of us!
He's about as far from normal as you can
get!
Naruto, slow down!
What are you trying to say?
He thinks his point in life is to kill
people!
Don't you see?
If this continues, Sasuke will die!
Relax.
No need to panic.
Huh?
You know, Sasuke and I weren't just
goofing around.
There's a reason we were so late getting
here.
I don't know what the hell you're up to.
You gonna stay in there forever?
Well, that's fine with me.
Stall all you want.
I can use the time getting ready for what
I've got in store for you.
Sensei?
You said there was a good reason you were
late.
What were you doing?
Well, it's kind of a long story.
Oh, come on!
Will you please do something?
This is no time for talking!
You're right, so shut up and watch.
Huh?
Keep your eye on Sasuke.
He's about to surprise you.
The little fool!
What does Gaara think he's doing?
The signal could come at any moment!
Are you ready?
I'm going to open it now.
I'm going to rip it open.
That's how you get it all out.
Everything inside will come spilling out.
Lots and lots of it.
Hm?
And I'll give it all to you.
I'm such a good boy, aren't I?
Are you watching, Mother?
Are you ready?
I'm ready.
What's that lunatic think he's doing?
How long is he going to stay in that
thing?
I don't know, but... he's not following
the plan.
He's no good to us like that.
It'll never work.
I say it's time to cut our losses and get
out of here!
Plan?
Hm?
But... it can't be.
If you wondered why I always insisted on
training Sasuke myself, now you know.
It's because he's like me.
A physical activation!
I see.
That's what you were doing all this time.
You were building his speed up to the
level required.
Exactly.
It's amazing!
His chakra is actually visible!
How is that even possible?
He's really mastered that technique
already?
So... this is what the Uchiha are capable
of.
Whoa!
I've never seen him do that before!
That bizarre noise... what sort of
technique is it?
It's a jab.
A what?
But this jab... is a jab like no other.
It's the only weapon in Kakashi's arsenal
he didn't copy from someone else.
It's the weapon of choice for
assassinations.
The secret of the jab is in the speed with
which it is delivered, and the ninja's
ability to focus its chakra at the point
of impact.
Once these two elements, speed and focus,
have attained a certain level,
it only becomes visible, and gives off
that distinctive sound that you hear,
like birds chirping.
It is this sound that gives the technique
its name.
Chidori!
That's impossible!
No one can penetrate his defenses!
No way!
I don't believe it!
That technique... it's Kakashi's!
Also known as Lightning Blade.
Why's that?
It got that name because
Kakashi once used it to cut a
bolt of lightning in half before
it could touch the ground.
Wow!
Cutting lightning in half!
Yeah, right.
These old guys and their war stories.
Whoa!
But whether called Thousand Birds or
Lightning Blade, it's a technique of
unimaginable power, requiring almost
inhuman levels of speed and chakra.
But once perfected, it
transforms a ninja's arm
into an indestructible
and invincible sword.
A dangerous technique not to be taught
lightly.
Yeah, you're one to talk.
Right, Lee?
Look at him.
A minute ago, he was worried that Sasuke
wasn't strong enough.
Now he thinks he's too strong.
And he's jealous.
What is this?
It's so warm and wet...
Mother... what is it?
Blood!
It's my blood!
What?
What's happening?
What is it?
Is it possible?
Gaara in pain?
What's that?
Oh no!
That arm!
Gaara!
You reckless little fool!
Is that thing taking over again?
I don't know.
This has never happened before.
I think he's hurt.
Oh, I remember the first time I saw it.
That thing.
It was awful.
Horrible.
Oh man.
Oh, I couldn't eat for a week.
DANGER!
I sense something... something bad...
I was right, he's hurt.
The shell broke before the change was
complete.
Something's different.
That's not the same look in his eyes that
I saw before.
What's going on?
Everything's getting all fuzzy.
Kagashi, do you feel it?
Yeah, a genjutsu.
Release!
Genjutsu... So, Kabuto's
already made his move, huh?
The time must be close.
It's coming.
Now, shall we begin?
There's the signal.
The operation has begun.
blacks are hurt.
How vile is this!?
Tschu check.
I love you Say it will wear down one油
Say it will wear down one油 A little pause.
.. and we are back.
A little pause... and we are back.